# Emilio Campos Jr.

(815) 543-8461 | ecampos.jr54@gmail.com | Chicago, IL (Open to relocation) | LinkedIn | GitHub

# Junior Software Engineer

I am a software engineering student learning Javascript and Python. I am well prepared to succeed as a software engineer based on my experience as an attorney where I handled up to 60 cases at once, independently and as part of a small team.

#### **SKILLS & EXPERTISE**

Javascript + HTML + CSS + Mongoose + Express + Node + React Problem Solving + Attentive to Detail + Exceptional verbal and written communication skills

## **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# Emilio's Blackjack - <a href="https://3campos.github.io/Project-1/">https://3campos.github.io/Project-1/</a> | Javascript | HTML | CSS

My take on the classic card game, Blackjack. I created multiple functions to allow play using a 52-card deck.

# Ollivanders - <a href="https://ollivanders-wands-app-ec.herokuapp.com/">https://ollivanders-wands-app-ec.herokuapp.com/</a> | Javascript | HTML | CSS

I built an inventory of wands from the point of Ollivander from the Harry Potter series. I added styling to make it appear "magical", including light blue shadowing for cards in the inventory and a levitation effect on the wands themselves.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Staff Attorney I | Catholic Charities Legal Assistance

June 2021 - April 2022

- Advised to over 100 clients' on their legal rights and advocated for them in court to reach favorable results
- Negotiated with multiple opposing counsels to reach optimal case resolution for clients

## Attorney at Law | Bryce Downey and Lenkov LLC

January 2021 - June 2021

- Litigated cases through settlement or trial including serving as sole attorney at trial and in negotiations
- Drafted legal analyses based on accident compensability, extent of medical treatment, and progressively evaluated trial exposure and settlement valuation of cases
- Argued for favorable trial exposure and settlement valuation by an arbitrator at pretrial hearings

#### Law Clerk

January 2020 - June 2020 & October. 2020 - January 2021

- Drafted multiple motions to dismiss and prepared exhibits
- Reviewed file materials to draft multiple lump sum settlement contracts and calculated damages

## Paralegal

March 2016 - August 2017

• Routinely analyzed hundreds of pages of medical records to draft concise summaries for expert physicians

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Software Engineering Immersive** | General Assembly | Remote

May 2022 - November 2022

An intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies.

## University of Illinois College of Law

May 2020

Juris Doctor

Latino Law Students Association: Treasurer; Alumni Scholarship Committee Delegate

Illinois Student Government: Senator for the College of Law (2018-2019)

### Loyola University Chicago

May 2013

Bachelor's of Business of Administration in Economics and Bachelor's of Business of Administration in Business Management